github.com/maryfarner18 medium.com/@maryfarner maryfarner.me

Software engineer experienced in JS and Ruby on Rails based web development, with background in CS and experience in finance and fitness. Possess strong people and project management skills to help small teams drive growth and success.

EDUCATION

Yale University, New Haven, CT

2012 - 2016

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science & Mathematics - GPA: 3.54/4.00

Women's Varsity Crew, walk-on, 2015 & 2016 Ivy League Champions, 7th Place NCAA Championship 2016

Flatiron School, New York, NY

2019 - 2020

Web Development Immersive Course

WORK EXPERIENCE

Project Manager + **Regional Director:** Chelsea Piers, New York, NY

2018 - 2019

- Managed enterprise-wide technology turnaround including assessment of the user experience and web presence, financial reporting and back office software tools, and business operational software.
- Managed 80+ instructors and three full-time employees with oversight of hiring and payroll processes.
- Led all operations and programming for the Group Fitness program at both locations in Manhattan and Brooklyn.
- Assisted in Chelsea Piers' expansion as a member of the original management team in Brooklyn.

FX Forwards Trader, Analyst: Bank of America Merrill Lynch, New York, NY

2017 - 2018

- Funded daily FX positions and supported senior traders in market-making, pricing, reporting, and risk management.
- Passed all requisite FINRA Licensing Exams (Series 7 and Series 63).

Associate Computer Scientist: USAF Research Lab, Information Directorate, NY

2014, 2015, 2016 – 2017

- Processed and analyzed data to provide for informed decision-making and increased security in AF-wide operations.
- Created a database with a graphical user interface for the storage and management of future Air Force aircraft and technology that was deployed base-wide and eventually adopted into the Air Force-wide wargaming community.
- Held a Top-Secret security clearance.

Teaching Assistant, CS50: Yale Computer Science Department, New Haven, CT

2015 - 2016

• Led teaching sections covering topics from lectures, held office hours assisting students with debugging and conceptualization of homework assignments, graded and provided feedback on students' assignments and tests.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, NodeJS, Java, Python, C, C++, SQLite, PostgreSQL, Linux, SQL, HTML, CSS, PHP

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Critter Crossing [Demo] [code]

Web-based arcade game similar to Frogger

• Implemented a JS React front end to display local JSON data

Rezzemay [Demo] [code]

App to automatically generate an online resume given user inputs

- Built JS React frontend with integration of Semantic UI and custom CSS
- Implemented a Ruby on Rails backend API to manage user authentication and data storage

On Target Fitness (Currently Working) [code]

Software to help manage a gym, from members, to personal training, to group fitness

• Created JS React frontend with Redux and Semantic UI libraries. Utilized Ruby on Rails backend for data API and